Larry Bogart Papers 2012.0088
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
- Series I: Inventory, undated, 1958-2001
  - Publications, clippings, correspondence, dummies, legal documents, photographs, manuscripts, 1958, 1961, 1964-1968, 1980, 1985-1989, 1991-1992, 1994-1995; 1.3 Linear feet Foldered (Box 33)
    Other Items: Correspondence to Larry Bogart on Galileo Probe (1991); Correspondence from George Wald to Larry Bogart; Dummies of covers and issues of Karen Westdyk's periodical "The Messenger" (1991-1992); Legal document "Certificate of Incorporation of Conservation Center, Inc." (1966); Correspondence from Larry Bogart (1965); Photograph, possibly Storm King mountain; Retrospectives remembering Larry Bogart.
    Other Topics: Possible Hazards of Electromagnetic Radiation; Food irradiation; Sara Shannon; Edward J. Sternglass; Beginning of Storm King Plant (1966).]
  - Fliers, clippings, publications, correspondence, posters, 1967-1968, 1973, 1976-1981, 1985-1986, 1988-1989; 1.3 Linear feet Foldered (Box 34)
    Articles and Publications: Flier "Human Beings: An Endangered Species" by Women Strike for Peace; Publication "Groundswell" by Nuclear Information and Resource Service (1979); Flier "Indian Point: 'An Accident waiting to Happen'" by Friends of the Hudson; Citizens Energy Council Publication "Nuclear Opponents" (1976); Publication "The Shut Down Times" by the Trojan Decommissioning Alliance (1979); Publication "Songs to Stop Seabrook: A Collection of Anti-Nuke Songs" (1978); U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission "News Releases" (1979-1980); Publication "Freedom" (1986); Publication "Northern Sun News" (1986); Publication "Citizen's Guide to U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Information" (1981); Publication "Citizen Alert" newsletter (1980); Publication "Radiation Death and Reports" by the Environmental Protection Agency (1973); Publication "Environmental News" from New Jersey Department of Environmental Protection (1986); Publication "The New Abolitionist" (1986); GAO Report "Canadian Power Imports: Update on Electricity Imports in the Northeast" (1989); Publication "The Messenger" (1989); Flier advertising book "Power Struggle: The Hundred-Year War Over Electricity" by Richard Rudolph and Scott Ridley; Publication "The Yankee Story" by Yankee Company (1968); Publication "Three Mile Island Alert Island Updates" (1980); German language Publication "Polizeiterror gegen AKW--Gegner: Erfahrungen aus der Wilster Marsch und Grohnde" (1977); Publication "Radiation in Air, Milk and Water" by New York State Department of Environmental Conservation (1978); Publication "Official Journal of the European Communities" (1976).
    Organizations: Radiation Victims Roundtable; Hanford Clearinghouse; Forelaws on Board; Environmental Education Center; Environmentalists for Full Employment; Japan Congress against A- and H-Bombs.
    Nuclear Plants: Seabrook; Shoreham; Rowe, Mass; Hanford; Trojan.
    Other Items: Poster for Hiroshima Day protests at General Electric Headquarters in Fairfield, CT, by Women's International Coalition; Correspondence to Larry Bogart at Citizens Energy Council (1980).]
  - Publications, clippings, notes, 1963, 1969, 1971, 1974, 1976-1979, 1982, 1984-1991, 1994; 1.3 Linear feet Foldered (Box 35)
    Articles and Publications: Publication "Lies of our Times: A Magazine to Correct the Record" (1991); Publication "Annual Report 1994: Pennsylvania Power & Light Company;" Publication "Facts about Proposal No. 1: A Plan to Rescue the State of New York from the Blight of Water Pollution" by National Audubon Society (1963); Article "A History of Federal Nuclear Safety Assessments: From Wash-740 Through the Reactor Safety Study" by Daniel F. Ford, Union of Concerned Scientists (1977); Article "Biological Hazards of Tritium" by Charles W. Huver (1971); Article "Radioactive Pollution from the Nuclear Power Industry" by Robert O. Pohl (1976); Flier "Radiation--A Fact of Life" by American Nuclear Society (1989); Publication "Atoms & Waste: Formerly the Radwaste Report" (1991); U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission "News Releases" (1991); Citizens Energy Council Publications "Nuclear Opponents" (1979) and "Nuclear Hazards" (1986); Publication "The Reagan Energy Plan: A Major Power Failure" (1982); Publication "Science and Public Affairs: Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists" (1971); Nuclear Information and Resource Service "Energy Fact Sheets;" Publication "Science for the People" (1978); Publication "The Great Atomic Fraud: Nuclear Power--A Multi-Billion Dollar Fiasco" by Mary Hays Weik (1971); Publication "The Food Irradiation Alert" (1985); Publication "C-10 Newsletter: Citizens Within the Ten Mile Radius" (1988); Publication "Science Reporter" (1963); Publication "WESPAC Newsletter" (1979); Publication "The Nuclear Resister" (1988).
    Organizations: Radioactive Waste Campaign; Citizens Committee for Protection of the Environment; Long Island Coalition for Safe Living; Citizens Energy Council.
    Other Topics: Food irradiation.]
  - Fliers, correspondence, publications, posters, ephemera, 1962, 1966-1967, 1974, 1976-1979, 1981, 1986-1987; 1.3 Linear feet Foldered (Box 36)
    Articles and Publications: Flier "The Most Important Thing In The World" by Nuclear Hazards Information Center (1978); Publication "Citizen Alert" (1987); Publication "Wisconsin Report" (1979); Flier "University of the Trees: Speed Tape Learning Institution;" Article "Radiation Roulette: Once You Start Gambling on Foreign Nuclear Reactors... How do you Stop?" by Harvey Wasserman (1979); Publication "Frogs in Hot Water" by Independent Citizens Research Foundation (1981); Citizens Energy Council publications "Nuclear Opponents" (1977) and "Nuclear Hazards" (1978-1979, 1981); Publication "Conscience and Military Tax Campaign" (1986); Article "The Nuclear Frontier" by Amanda Spake; Publication "The Waste Paper" by the Sierra Club (1979); Publication "Campus Review" (1987); Publication "A Vital Message from Lao Russell" (1981); Publication "Citizen's Clearinghouse for Hazardous Wastes Action Bulletin" (1987); Publication "The Case for the People by the People in a Time of Technological Tyrrany" by Phi Beta Kappa Environmental Study Group (1976); Publication "The Progressive" (1974); Publication "Bullettin: The Anti-Pollution League" (1967); Flier "10 Myths of Food Irradiation" by NYPIRG (1986).
    Organizations: Citizens Energy Council; Chernobyl Child Relief Fund; New Hampshire Clamshell Alliance; The Conservation Center.
    Nuclear Plants: Indian Point, Seabrook.
    Other Items: Nuclear Information and Resource Service Energy Fact Sheet 10: Emergency Planning; Friends of the Hudson Bumper Stickers, reading "People Inside," with radioactive emblem; Poster "I Was the Only Victim of Three Mile Island" (1979); Correspondence from Larry Bogart (1966).]
  - Publications, transcripts, clippings, posters, correspondence, fliers, postcards, 1961-1962, 1966, 1975-1977, 1979-1981, 1983, 1987-1989; 1.3 Linear feet Foldered (Box 37)
    Articles and Publications: German publication "Umwelt Akut" (1976); Article "European Opposition to Nuclear Plants: An Overview' by Petra Karin Kelly (1977); Transcript of speech "6 August 1977 Hiroshima Day Rally: Sydney" by Petra Karin Kelly; Publication "Why the Australian Labor Party Opposes Uranium Mining" (1976); Publication "Not Man Apart" by Friends of the Earth (1980); Publication "Campaign Against Nuclear power Newsletter" (1980); U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission "News Releases" (1980); Citizens Energy Council publications "Nuclear Hazards" (1980) and "Energy News Digest" (1983); Publication "Public Power Weekly" (1980); Flier "How to Save Gasoline... And Money" by U.S. Department of Energy (1979); Publication "Environmentalists for Full Employment Special Report" (1980); Nuclear Information and Resource Service publication "Groundswell" (1980); Publication "Radioactivist Report" by Keystone Alliance (1980); Publication "Three Mile Island Alert Island Updates" (1980); Publication "Women Strike for Peace New York Peaceletter;" Publication "Stevens Energy Forum" (1980); Article "Taste and Smell Implications of the Hypothetical Emission of Nonradioactive Chemicals at Three Mile Island" by Richard Martyr (1989); Publication "The What and Why of Atomic Power" by John F. Hogerton (1966); Articles "Haste Makes Waste" and "Fading Fast: The Rising Costs, Declining Performance and Increasing Problems at Older Nuclear Reactors" by Joseph Kriesberg (1987); Publication "Palmetto Nuclear Report" (1980); Publication "Radiation Events Monitor (1987); Publication "Union of Concerned Scientists Nucleus" (1988).
    Organizations: Commission of the European Communities; Friends of the Hudson; Catskill Mountain Historical Association; Council for Chemical Education; The Peace Taxpayers; New England Coalition on Nuclear Pollution, Inc.; Clamshell Alliance; Childhood Cancer Research Institute.
    Nuclear Plants: Indian Point; Three Mile Island; Hartsville (Alabama); Hanford; Seabrook; Yankee Rowe; Pilgrim.
    Other Items: German Language publications; Poster "We Are Angry Women" by Women Strike for Peace (1980); Correspondence to and from Larry Bogart; Poster "Walk March 23-28 for a Non-Nuclear Jersey" by SEA Alliance; Postcard, dated 1910.
    Other Topics: Uranium Mining in Australia, and threat to Aboriginal peoples.]
  - Fliers, posters, clippings, publications, maps, ephemera, 1965, 1969, 1974-1975, 1979-1980, 1983-1987, 1990, 1992, 1997-1998, 2000; 1.3 Foldered (Box 38)
    Articles and Publications: Flier for "First Global Radiation Victims Conference" in New York (1987); Article "Post Reagan: A Time of Hope" by David McReynolds, War Resisters League (1987); Flier on Indian Point by Neighbors to Remove the Risk, not the People; Publication "The Defense Monitor" by Center for Defense Information (1987); Publication "Background Report to the national Council of Churches of Christ in the U.S.A. in Support of the Plutonium Economy: A Statement of Concern" (1975); Article "Biological Effects of Tritium" by Charles W. Huver (1969); Article "Nuclear Power and Nuclear Bombs" by Amory B. Lovins, L. Hunter Lovins, and Leonard Ross (1980); Publication "Natural Resources Defense Council Newsletter" (1974); Citizens Energy Council Publication "Energy News Digest" (1985); Flier "Standing for Truth about Radiation Presents: Recent Studies of Low Level Radiation and Implications for Medicine and the Nuclear Industry" (1998); Publication "Earth First!" (1997); Publication "E: The Environmental Magazine" (1992); Flier "A Very Ugly Fact about Every Nuclear Power Plant" by Natural Resources Defense Council; Publication "Akwesasne Notes: A Journal for Native and Natural Peoples" (1980); Nuclear Information and Resource Service publication "Groundswell" (1985); Publication "Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists" (1983); U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission "News Releases" (1990); Publication "Clean Air and Water in a Complex Society" by E.I. DuPont de Nemours and Company (1965); Publication "Should we Rely on Nuclear Power to Help Supply our Future Energy Needs?" by The Advocates, WGBH Boston; Publication "Critical Mass Journal" (1979).
    Organizations: Union of Concerned Scientists; U.S. Council for Energy Awareness (pro-nuclear organization).
    Nuclear Plants: Seabrook, Indian Point, Three Mile Island.
    Other Items: "Sterling Forest Timeline" by James A. Hunter, sent to Karen Westdyk; Conference Poster "Nuclear Realities: From Victim to Activist" (1983); Map of military targets and fallout from nuclear weapons; Stickers, reading "Shut them All Down At Once For Good!".
    Other Topics: Environmental contamination leading to frog mutation and extinction; Correspondence by Joanna R. Macy to Dalai Lama on nuclear power; Three Mile Island accident.]
  - Publications, clippings, fliers, correspondence, 1963, 1973, 1979-1980, 1982, 1985, 1989-1991, 1993; 1.3 Linear feet Foldered (Box 39)
    Articles and Publications: Publication "The Waste Paper" by the Sierra Club Radioactive Waste Campaign (1979); Article "The Biological Effects of Low-Level Ionizing Radiation" by Arthur C. Upton (Scientific American, 1982); Publication "Clamshell Alliance News" (1979); Flier "The Challenge of Peace" by Christopher News Notes; U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission "News Releases" (1980; 1991); Publication "Federal Register, Part II: Nuclear Regulatory Commission" (1993); Publications from Three Mile Island Aler, Inc. on "The Three Mile Island Accident 10th Anniversary" includeing "Nuclear Power Facts" and "Three Mile Island Facts;" Publication "Confuse and Deceive: The Great Nuclear Brainwash" by Independent Citizens Research Foundation; Citizens Energy Council Publications "Nuclear Hazards Versus Alternative Energies" (1980) and "Energy News Digest" (1985); Publication "Radioactive Waste Campaign Waste Paper" (1989); Publication "Before and After Chernobyl: Nuclear Power in Crisis: A Country by Country Report" by Asa Moberg; Article "Methanol: A Versatile Fuel for Immediate Use" by T.B. Reed and R.M. Lerner (1973); Article "Biomass Energy Refineries for Production of Food and Fertilizer" by Thomas B. Reed; Publication "On The Watch" from New England Coalition on Nuclear Pollution (1990); Publication "Science Reporter" by Friends of the Museum of Science and Technology" (1963)
    Organizations: Friends of the Hudson; Citizens Energy Council.
  - Correspondence, publications, fliers, maps, 1963, 1966, 1974, 1976-1979, 1981-1982, 1985-1989, 1991; 1.3 Linear feet Foldered (Box 40)
    Articles and Publications: Publication "Red Cross Nuclear Site Emergency Response Plan" for Perry Nuclear Plants (Ohio), 1963; Flier "The Most Important Thing in the World" by Nuclear Hazards Information Center (1978); Publication "The Nuclear Resister" (1986); Article "The Industry's 'Nuclear Future' Teeters" by Chris Nord (1988); Publication "Forelaws on Board" (1987); Publication "The Radioactivist: Clamshell Alliance News" (1988); Flier "The Yankee Plant, Rowe, Massachusetts: Producing Electricity in Massachusetts for Over 28 Years" by Yankee Atomic Electric Company; Publication "The Hanford Journal" (1987); Publication "The Spotlight on Truth in Politics" (1985); Publication "Three Mile Island Alert Island Updates" (1982); U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission "News Releases" (1977, 1982); Article "A White Paper XXVI: 38 Factual Steps that Early Indicated the Demise of Marble Hill" by Fred Hauck, Save the Valley, Inc. (1985); Flier "Nuclear Power: Problem or Progress" by West Michigan Environmental Action Council; Publication "Conscience and Military Tax Campaign" (1987); Publication "Peace Network News" (1987); Publication "The Nuclear Monitor" by Nuclear Information and Resource Service (1987); Flier "Paths to Empowerment: A Nuclear Free Zone Primer;" Publication "Washington Report" (1987); Article "Nuclear Waste Management in Western Europe" by Simon Rippon (1987); Flier "Clearwater and the Hudson;" Publication "C-10 Newsletter: Citizens Within the Ten Mile Radius" (1991); Publication "Citizen Alert" (1976); Article "A New Concept for Solar Energy Thermal Conversion" by J.J. Cuomo, J.F. Ziegler, and J.M. Woodall (1974); Publication "WESPAC Newsletter" (1977).
    Organizations: The Conservation Center; Radioactive Waste Campaign; League Against Nuclear Dangers; Hudson Valley Citizens' Watch on Nuclear Safety.
    Nuclear Plants: Perry; Yankee Rowe; Hanford; Shoreham; Indian Point; Seabrook; Vermont Yankee; Three Mile Island; Nine Mile Point.
    Other Items: Clippings on Global Radiation Victims' Conference; Instructions for "The Nuclear Energy Game" (1982); Map "Commercial Nuclear Power Stations in the U.S.--Operable, Under Construction, or Ordered--August 1, 1985" by Nuclear News; Women Strike for Peace Petition against the Neutron Bomb.]
  - Publications, clippings, posters, dummies, photographs, transcripts, correspondence, 1959, 1965-1968, 1970, 1973, 1975, 1977-1981, 1985-1987, 1989-1990; 1.3 Linear feet Foldered (Box 41)
    Articles and Publications: Article "Statement: Friends of the Hudson, Mountainville, New York, Larry Bogart, Director" (1965); Publication "Sceneic Hudson Preservation Conference Bulletin" (1965); Publication "Watch on the Hudson" by Friends of the Hudson (1978); Article "A Bill to Provide for the Establishment of the Hudson Highlands National Scenic Riverway in the State of New York and for Other Purposes" (1989); Article "Goldenclub, a Threatened Plant in the Tidal Hudson River" by Erik Kiviat; Publication "kV Alliance Newsletter" (1977); Publication "Mid-Hudson Nuclear Opponents, Inc." newsletter (1978); Publication "A Primer on Nuclear Wastes for Governor Carey" by Friends of the Hudson; Publication "New York State Energy Research and Development Authority (NYSERDA) Review" (1978); U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission "News Releases" (1977, 1989); Flier "Active Today or Radioactive Tomorrow: Rally in Albany, Oct. 30 for Action Against Nuclear Wastes;" Flier "While Millions of Americans Oppose Nuclear Power Plants" by Friends of the Hudson; Publication "Westchester People's Action Coalition (WESPAC) Newsletter" (1977); Publication "Rodale's Environmental Action Bulletin" (1977); Publication "Your Health Problems" by Dr. Alice Chase (1959); Article "Ocean Power: Is the U.S. Afraid of it" by John F. Judge (1977); Publication "The Hard Truth About our Energy Future" by Dr. Arthur M. Bueche (1977); Legal document "Before the State of New York Board on Electrical Generation Siting and the Environment In the Matter of Case 80006, And Before the Atomic Safety and Licensing Board, In the Matter of the Power Authority of the State of New York... Prepared Testimony of Edward W. Radle and Wayne P. Elliott" (1979); Publication "Three Mile Island Alert Island Updates" (1980); Publication "Survival Summer News" (1980); Publication "Wisconsin Report" (1981); Article "The Case of the Hidden Agenda" by Leland P. Bradford; Publication "National Coal Policy Conference, Inc. Newsletter" (1970); Publication "Central New York Environment" (1987); Publication "Scientists Urge Five-Year Moratorium on Construction of Nuclear Power Plants" by Alameda Times Star (1970); Citizens Energy Council Publications "People and Power" (1975) and "Nuclear Hazards (1981, 1986); Publication "Chernobyl-on-the-Hudson: New York City's Nuclear Reactor" by New York Greens.
    Organizations: Friends of the Hudson; Women's International Coalition; Nuclear Hazards Information Center; Citizens for Safe Power Transmission; Clamshell Alliance; Union of Concerned Scientists; Stop PASNY Alliance; New England Coalition on Nuclear Pollution; Citizens Energy Council.
    Nuclear Plants: Indian Point; Sterling; Vermont Yankee; Nine Mile Point; Limerick; Seabrook.
    Other Items: Correspondence to and from Larry Bogart at Friends of the Hudson (1965); Script for documentary film "Requiem for a River" by Peter Jones; Larry Bogart's Correspondence with Julia Lamb and Dr. Albert Richard Lamb, Jr.; Letter from Joy Macnulty, Friends of the Hudson, to New York Governor Hugh L. Carey; Poster for Anti-Nuclear Rally against seabrook by New York Shad Alliance; Mailing list of "Moratorium Supporters" (1973); Photographs, possibly Hudson River; Dummies of publications; Transcript of "60 Minutes," March 2, 1986.]